Noah H. Guale

+1(847)-868-4949

noahquale@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Chemical Engineering student with an interest in Computer Programming. Wide breadth of experience and knowledge in computer science with an emphasis on Application Development and cloud computing platforms. Passionate, driven, and achievement oriented with excellent verbal and written communication skills. Able to work effectively in managing high-pressure and demanding work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern - Application Development

Cloudbakers | Qwinix | Chicago, IL

May 2021 - Present

- Developed a demo web application (Point-Of-Sale System) used for sales and client educational purposes demonstrate Cloudbakers | Qwinix proficiency with application design and show what the Google Cloud Platform can offer.
- Used Google Cloud Platform services including App Engine and BigQuery
- Implemented Looker Embedded Dashboards to the demo web application to show clients an interactive and highly curated data experience.
- Involved in infrastructure as code, execution plans, and change automation using Terraform.

Computer Programmer

Artist Influence | NYC, NY

September 2020 - December 2020

- Code refactored Python scripts that maximized customer's social media presence in Spotify and Apple Music.
- Coordinated effectively among a team of coders to construct a streamline to meet priority deadlines.

Service Experience Representative

Nordstrom | Oakbrook, IL

October 2020 - May 2021

- Build positive relations with customers from one the largest stores in the country.
- Operate points of sales systems across multiple operating systems, such as Google Services, Windows, and iOS.
- Provide exceptional customer service and defuse customer situations by resolving them in a timely and effective manner.

Freelance Graphic Designer

Chicago, IL

May 2015 - Present

- Successfully created and implemented numerous graphic design projects from concept through completion.
- Worked closely with clients to develop a vision, conceive designs, and construct products that expanded the client's brand

Research Intern - Department of Chemical & Biological Engineering - Amaral Lab

Northwestern University | Evanston, IL

May 2017 - May 2018

- Identifying and analyzing mutation probabilities of the viral genome of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) using Python and library BioPython.
- Imported and analyzed over 3000 genotypes of the virus.
- Developed an alignment tool, to align different viral genotypes and determined the mutation probabilities through the viral gene map.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering

Expected Graduation (2022)

University of Illinois at Chicago

Chicago, IL

SKILLS/TOOLS:

Skills: Python, Django, C++, MatLab, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, Google Cloud Platform, Google App Engine, Google Cloud Run, Google Cloud Functions, Google Cloud SQL, Terraform

Software/Applications: Visual Studio Code, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook, Adobe Create Cloud Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Lightroom, Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)